<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Vocabulary xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://vocabsservices.getty.edu/Schemas/AAT/AATGetSubject.xsd">
  <Subject Subject_ID="300019188">
    <Parent_Relationships>
      <Preferred_Parent>
        <Parent_Subject_ID>300174553</Parent_Subject_ID>
        <Relationship_Type>Parent/Child</Relationship_Type>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Parent_String>Cham periods [300174553], Cham (Southeast Asian culture) [300019181], Vietnamese regional styles and periods [300019242], Vietnamese (culture or style) [300019239], Southeast Asian [300120146], Asian [300018279], styles, periods, and cultures by region [300111079], Styles and Periods (hierarchy name) [300015646], Styles and Periods Facet [300264088]</Parent_String>
        <Hier_Rel_Type>Genus/Species-BTG</Hier_Rel_Type>
      </Preferred_Parent>
    </Parent_Relationships>
    <Descriptive_Notes>
      <Descriptive_Note>
        <Note_Text>Refers to the period in Champa associated with the royal monastery complex Dong-Duong founded by King Indravarman II (875-889 CE) and prevailing in the region from the ninth to the early tenth century. Architectural features from this period are based on the Dong-Duong complex and include brick construction, sanctuaries grouped within inner enclosures, pillared halls, interior and exterior piers supporting the stupa, multi-story brick kalan, columnar structures known as stambahs similar in shape to Buddhist tower-stupas, a long hall known as a vih'ra containing Buddha images, and altars restrictively placed against walls. In sculpture, the period is driven by the religious trend of Mahayana Buddhism and features Buddha figures draped in the Chinese manner, dv'rap'las figures with fierce expressions, thick lips, stylized ears, and close-cropped short side whiskers, bronze sculptures of Buddha cast by the lost-wax process, bas-reliefs decorating tympana and altars, exhibiting various royal personages in stylized actions, and elephant statues with the hind legs bent and with the head turned forwards or trunk raised. Shaivite heads and female images of Tara produced in this period feature strong frontality and exaggerated features.</Note_Text>
        <Note_Language>English</Note_Language>
        <Note_Contributors>
          <Note_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000000/VP</Contributor_id>
          </Note_Contributor>
        </Note_Contributors>
        <Note_Sources>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000099620/Legacy AAT data</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
        </Note_Sources>
      </Descriptive_Note>
      <Descriptive_Note>
        <Note_Text>Se refiere al período en Champa asociado con el complejo del monasterio real Dong-Duong fundado por el Rey Indravarman II (875-889 DC) imperante en la región desde el siglo noveno a principios del siglo décimo. Los rasgos arquitectónicos de este período se basan en el complejo Dong-Duong e incluyen construcción de ladrillo, santuarios agrupados dentro de los cercos interiores, vestíbulos sostenidos con pilares, columnas interiores y exteriores que sostienen el stupa, kalan de ladrillo, estructuras columnares conocidas como stambahs similares en forma a las torres-stupas budistas, un vestíbulo largo conocido como un vih'ra que contiene imágenes de Buda, y altares restrictivamente ubicados contra las paredes. En escultura, el período es guiado por la tendencia religiosa del Budismo de Mahayana y ofrece figuras de Buda cubiertas con ropajes a la manera china, las figuras dv'rap'las con expresiones feroces, labios gruesos, orejas estilizadas, y patillas muy cortas, esculturas de vaciado de bronce de Buda por el proceso de perdida de cera, bajo relieves que decoran tympana y altares, exhibiendo varios personajes reales en acciones estilizadas, y estatuas de elefante con las patas posteriores dobladas y con la cabeza doblada hacia adelante o torso levantado. La cabeza de Shaivite y las imágenes femeninas de Tara producidas en este período ofrecen enérgica frontalidad y rasgos exagerados.</Note_Text>
        <Note_Language>Spanish</Note_Language>
        <Note_Contributors>
          <Note_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000131/CDBP-SNPC</Contributor_id>
          </Note_Contributor>
        </Note_Contributors>
        <Note_Sources>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000051034/TAA database (2000-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
        </Note_Sources>
      </Descriptive_Note>
      <Descriptive_Note>
        <Note_Text>Verwijst naar de periode Champa die wordt geassocieerd met het koninklijke kloostercomplex Dong-Duong dat werd gesticht door koning Indravarman II (875-889 n. Chr.) en dat in het gebied floreerde van de 9de tot de vroege 10de eeuw. Bouwkundige kenmerken uit deze periode zijn gebaseerd op het Dong-Duong-complex en bestaan onder andere uit in baksteen opgetrokken heiligdommen die zijn gegroepeerd binnen interne omheiningen, zalen met pilaren, interne en externe penanten ter ondersteuning van de stupa, stenen kalan met meerdere verdiepingen, zuilconstructies die bekend zijn als stambah's en die qua vorm vergelijkbaar zijn met boeddhistische torenstupa's, een lange zaal die de vih'ra wordt genoemd en die beelden van Boeddha bevat, en altaren die tegen muren zijn geplaatst. In de beeldhouwkunst manifesteert deze periode zich in de religieuze trend van het Mahayana-boeddhisme, gekenmerkt door Boeddha-figuren die op Chinese wijze zijn gekleed, dv'rap'las-figuren met krachtige uitdrukkingen, dikke lippen, gestileerde oren en kortgeknipte bakkebaarden, bronzen beelden van Boeddha die zijn gegoten met behulp van het verlorenwasgietprocédé, bas-reliëfs die timpanen en altaren decoreren, en die verschillende koninklijke personages tonen in gestileerde handelingen, beelden van olifanten met gebogen achterpoten en met hun kop naar voren of met hun lichaam opgericht. Shaivitische koppen en vrouwelijke afbeeldingen van Tara uit deze periode worden gekenmerkt door een sterke frontaliteit en overdreven gelaatstrekken.</Note_Text>
        <Note_Language>Dutch</Note_Language>
        <Note_Contributors>
          <Note_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000205/AAT-Ned</Contributor_id>
          </Note_Contributor>
        </Note_Contributors>
        <Note_Sources>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000113770/AAT-Ned (1994-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
        </Note_Sources>
      </Descriptive_Note>
    </Descriptive_Notes>
    <Record_Type>Concept</Record_Type>
    <Merged_Status>Merged</Merged_Status>
    <Sort_Order>3500</Sort_Order>
    <Terms>
      <Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>Dong-duong</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000019188</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70051/English</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Adjectival</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70641/Spanish</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70261/Dutch</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000000/VP</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000131/CDBP-SNPC</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000205/AAT-Ned</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000008951/Pearman, CMA Slide Library Classification (1980s)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000045262/Grove Dictionary of Art online (1999-2002)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>"Dong Duong;" "Champa: Sculpture: Late 9th century ad-the early 10th: Dong-duong style;"  "Champa: Architecture: Religious: Late 9th century-the early 10th: Dong-duong style" Accessed 7/31/00</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000016711/Groslier, Indo-China (1962)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>255</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000025171/Lee, History of Far Eastern Art (1982)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>533</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000051034/TAA database (2000-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000113770/AAT-Ned (1994-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>Dong-du'o'ng</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000268017</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70051/English</Language>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Used For Term</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000000/VP</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000040971/University of Michigan Slide Classification (n.d.)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
    </Terms>
    <Subject_Contributors>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000000/VP</Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000131/CDBP-SNPC</Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000205/AAT-Ned</Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
    </Subject_Contributors>
    <Subject_Sources>
      <Subject_Source>
        <Source>
          <Source_ID>2000113770/AAT-Ned (1994-)</Source_ID>
        </Source>
      </Subject_Source>
    </Subject_Sources>
  </Subject>
</Vocabulary>