<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Vocabulary xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://vocabsservices.getty.edu/Schemas/AAT/AATGetSubject.xsd">
  <Subject Subject_ID="300021614">
    <Parent_Relationships>
      <Preferred_Parent>
        <Parent_Subject_ID>300244021</Parent_Subject_ID>
        <Relationship_Type>Parent/Child</Relationship_Type>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Parent_String>Anatolian Islamic styles and periods after Manzikert [300244021], Islamic World dynastic styles and periods [300021520], Islamic World, The [300021516], styles, periods, and cultures by region [300111079], Styles and Periods (hierarchy name) [300015646], Styles and Periods Facet [300264088]</Parent_String>
        <Hier_Rel_Type>Genus/Species-BTG</Hier_Rel_Type>
      </Preferred_Parent>
    </Parent_Relationships>
    <Descriptive_Notes>
      <Descriptive_Note>
        <Note_Text>Refers to the style and period associated with the reign of the Islamic dynasty that began to rule in Anatolia in 1281 until the promulgation of the Constitution of the Turkish Republic in 1924. Under the support of Ottoman sultans, a distinct architectural style developed that combined the Islamic traditions of Anatolia, Iran, and Syria with those of the Classical world and Byzantium. The result was a rationalist approach that favored spatial unity and clarity, the most important structure being the kulliye, a building complex combining religious, educational and charitable buildings. The main architectural theme of this complex was the domed square unit and combinations of varying spatial and architectonic expressions. The mosque, and in some cases the mosque-convent, was the crowning achievement. Under the conquest of Constantinople and the establishment of new administrative palaces across the empire, the relationship between Ottoman patrons and the artist became centralized. A corps of court architects employed architects of different ranks, and controlled all building activity throughout the empire. A community of craftsman brought together societies of artists and craftsman, forming the imperial design studio where illuminated manuscripts, tiles, woodwork, carved stone, jade, and metal objects, along with carpets and textiles were produced. These works typically chronicled the important events of a sultan's rule. During the 18th and 19th century, Ottoman art was increasingly westernized in style, often incorporating elements of European Baroque style.</Note_Text>
        <Note_Language>English</Note_Language>
        <Note_Contributors>
          <Note_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000000/VP</Contributor_id>
          </Note_Contributor>
        </Note_Contributors>
        <Note_Sources>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000026081/Levey, World of Ottoman Art (1975)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000045262/Grove Dictionary of Art online (1999-2002)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
        </Note_Sources>
      </Descriptive_Note>
      <Descriptive_Note>
        <Note_Text>Se refiere al estilo y periodo asociado al reinado de la dinastía islámica que comenzó a gobernar en Anatolia en 1281 hasta la promulgación de la constitución de la República de Turquía en 1924. Se desarrolló un estilo arquitectónico característico bajo el apoyo de los sultanes otomanos, que combinaba la tradición islámica de Anatolia, Irán y Siria con aquellas del mundo clásico y de Bizancio. Dio como resultado un acercamiento racionalista que favoreció la unidad espacial y la claridad, siendo la estructura más importante el kulliye, un complejo constructivo que combina la religión, la educación y edificios para la caridad. El tema arquitectónico principal de este complejo era la cúpula cuadrada y una combinación que varía el espacio y expresión arquitectónica. La mezquita y en algunos casos mezquitas-conventos, correspondieron a los mayores logros. Bajo la conquista de Constantinopla y el establecimiento de nuevos palacios administrativos a lo largo del imperio, la relación entre los patrones otomanos y los artistas se centralizó. Un cuerpo de arquitectos de la corte empleó arquitectos de diferentes rangos y controló toda actividad constructiva a lo largo del imperio. Una comunidad de artesanos reunió a sociedades de artistas y artesanos, formando una cámara de diseño imperial que iluminó manuscritos, azulejos, trabajos en madera, tallado en piedra, jade y objetos de metal, así como también producían alfombras y textiles. Típicamente, estos trabajos informaban sobre los importantes eventos del gobierno del sultán. Durante los siglox XVIII y XIX, el arte otomano incorporó elementos del estilo barroco europeo.
</Note_Text>
        <Note_Language>Spanish</Note_Language>
        <Note_Contributors>
          <Note_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000131/CDBP-SNPC</Contributor_id>
          </Note_Contributor>
        </Note_Contributors>
        <Note_Sources>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000051034/TAA database (2000-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
        </Note_Sources>
      </Descriptive_Note>
      <Descriptive_Note>
        <Note_Text>Verwijst naar de stijl en periode die in verband worden gebracht met de heerschappij van de islamitische dynastie die aan de macht kwam in Anatolië in 1281 tot de afkondiging van de grondwet van de republiek Turkije in 1924. Met ondersteuning van de Osmaanse sultans ontwikkelde zich een opvallende architectuurstijl waarin de islamitische tradities van Anatolië, Iran en Syrië werden gecombineerd met de tradities van de klassieke wereld en Byzantium. Het resultaat was een rationalistische benadering met een hoofdrol voor ruimtelijke eenheid en helderheid, met als belangrijkste structuur de kulliye, een complex met gebouwen voor religieuze, educatieve en charitatieve doeleinden. Het belangrijkste bouwkundige thema van dit complex was een overkoepelde vierkante ruimte en combinaties van uiteenlopende ruimtelijke en architectonische expressies. De moskee, en in sommige gevallen het moskee-klooster, vormde het hoogtepunt. Na de verovering van Constantinopel en de vestiging van nieuwe administratieve paleizen in het hele rijk, werd de relatie tussen Osmaanse beschermheren en de kunstenaar gecentraliseerd. Een staf van hofarchitecten nam architecten van verschillende rangen en standen in dienst en controleerde alle bouwactivieiten in het rijk. Een gemeenschap van kunstenaars en ambachtslieden werkte voor de centrale ontwerpstudio, waar versierde manuscripten, tegelwerk, houtsnijwerk, beeldhouwwerk, jade en metalen voorwerpen werden vervaardigd, evenals tapijten en stoffen. Met deze werken werden gewoonlijk de belangrijke momenten tijdens de heerschappij van de sultan gememoreerd. In de 18de en 19de eeuw raakte de Osmaanse kunst steeds meer verwesterd, vaak met elementen van de Europese barokstijl.</Note_Text>
        <Note_Language>Dutch</Note_Language>
        <Note_Contributors>
          <Note_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000205/AAT-Ned</Contributor_id>
          </Note_Contributor>
        </Note_Contributors>
        <Note_Sources>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000113770/AAT-Ned (1994-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000052378/Winkler Prins Encyclopedie (1990)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
        </Note_Sources>
      </Descriptive_Note>
      <Descriptive_Note>
        <Note_Text>用來表示與此一伊斯蘭王朝有關的風格與時代；鄂圖曼王朝從西元 1281 年開始統治安那托利亞（Anatolia），並於西元 1924 年土耳其共和國憲法公佈後結束統治。在鄂圖曼蘇丹人的支持下，此一時期發展出一種特有的建築風格。此一建築風格融合了安那托利亞、伊朗與敘利亞的伊斯蘭傳統，以及古典世界與拜占庭的建築傳統；這樣的建築風格因而呈現出理性主義的態度，喜好鮮明統一的空間格局。其中最重要的ㄧ種結構稱為庫利葉（kulliye），是一種融合宗教、教育及慈善服務建築物的複合建築。此種複合建築的建築主題包括具有圓屋頂的廣場以及各式空間與建築表現手法的結合。清真寺（在某些情況下，亦稱為清真寺修道院）為此一時期的最大建築成就。由於鄂圖曼王朝佔領了君士坦丁堡，並且在其帝國內大興新的行宮，因而使得鄂圖曼的資助者與藝術家之間的關係變得集中化。一組宮廷建築師會雇用不同階級的建築師，並且掌管帝國內所有的建築活動。由工匠所組成的社群集結了不同的藝術家與工匠團體，成立了帝國設計工作室，於此製作手稿、瓷磚、木製品、石雕、玉製品、金屬製品、地毯以及紡織品。這些作品記載了在蘇丹人統治之下，鄂圖曼王朝曾經發生的重大事件。在西元十八與十九世紀期間，鄂圖曼藝術風格逐漸西化，時常融入歐洲巴洛克風格的元素。</Note_Text>
        <Note_Language>Chinese (traditional)</Note_Language>
        <Note_Contributors>
          <Note_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000250/AS-Academia Sinica</Contributor_id>
          </Note_Contributor>
        </Note_Contributors>
        <Note_Sources>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000079740/AS-Academia Sinica data (2014-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
        </Note_Sources>
      </Descriptive_Note>
      <Descriptive_Note>
        <Note_Text>Refere-se ao estilo e período associados ao reinado da dinastia islâmica que começou a governar a Anatólia em 1281 até a promulgação da Constituição da República Turca em 1924. Sob o apoio dos sultões otomanos, desenvolveu-se um estilo arquitetônico distinto que combinava o Tradições islâmicas da Anatólia, Irã e Síria com as do mundo clássico e de Bizâncio. O resultado foi uma abordagem racionalista que favoreceu a unidade e clareza espacial, sendo a estrutura mais importante o kulliye, um edifício complexo que combina edifícios religiosos, educacionais e de caridade. O principal tema arquitetônico deste complexo foi a unidade quadrada abobadada e combinações de várias expressões espaciais e arquitetônicas. A mesquita, e em alguns casos a mesquita-convento, foi o coroamento. Sob a conquista de Constantinopla e o estabelecimento de novos palácios administrativos em todo o império, a relação entre os patronos otomanos e o artista tornou-se centralizada. Um corpo de arquitetos da corte empregava arquitetos de diferentes níveis e controlava todas as atividades de construção em todo o império. Uma comunidade de artesãos reunia sociedades de artistas e artesãos, formando o ateliê de design imperial onde eram produzidos manuscritos iluminados, azulejos, trabalhos em madeira, pedra esculpida, jade e objetos de metal, além de tapetes e tecidos. Essas obras geralmente narravam os eventos importantes do governo de um sultão. Durante os séculos XVIII e XIX, a arte otomana foi cada vez mais ocidentalizada em estilo, muitas vezes incorporando elementos do estilo barroco europeu.</Note_Text>
        <Note_Language>Portuguese</Note_Language>
        <Note_Contributors>
          <Note_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000316/CVAA-BR</Contributor_id>
          </Note_Contributor>
        </Note_Contributors>
        <Note_Sources>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000109633/CVAA-BR Consortium (2020-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
        </Note_Sources>
      </Descriptive_Note>
    </Descriptive_Notes>
    <Record_Type>Concept</Record_Type>
    <Merged_Status>Merged</Merged_Status>
    <Sort_Order>75</Sort_Order>
    <Terms>
      <Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>Ottoman</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000021614</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70051/English</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>style</Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Adjectival</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000000/VP</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000088/GCI</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000003021/Arts of Islam (1976)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>47</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000046657/Avery Index (1963-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>(source AAT) - subhead.</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000003821/Burckhardt, Art of Islam (1976)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>204</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000033011/Papadopoulo, Islam and Muslim Art (1979)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>628</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000051089/AATA database (2002-) </Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>126886 checked 26 January 2012</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>Osmanli</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000114892</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70051/English</Language>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Used For Term</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000000/VP</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000035091/Rice, Islamic Art (1965)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>265</Page>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>Ottoman Turks</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000114883</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70051/English</Language>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Used For Term</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000000/VP</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000016141/Gray, Persian Painting (1961)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>183</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000035091/Rice, Islamic Art (1965)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>285</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>Turks, Ottoman</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000167030</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70051/English</Language>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Used For Term</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000000/VP</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000094828/Getty Vocabulary Program rules</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>Otomano</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000422831</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70641/Spanish</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70543/Portuguese</Language>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>estilo</Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Alternate Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Singular Noun</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000131/CDBP-SNPC</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000316/CVAA-BR</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000048967/Lévèque y Ménant, Pintura Islámica e india (1969)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>47</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000109633/CVAA-BR Consortium (2020-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>Osmaans</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000475028</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70261/Dutch</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000205/AAT-Ned</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000113770/AAT-Ned (1994-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000052378/Winkler Prins Encyclopedie (1990)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Unknown</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>鄂圖曼帝國</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000584204</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>72551/Chinese (traditional)</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>風格</Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000250/AS-Academia Sinica</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000093499/國家教育研究院－雙語詞彙、學術名詞暨辭書資訊網 28 July, 2014</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>July 6, 2012</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000093495/大英百科全書線上繁體中文版</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>July 6, 2012</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000078102/文馨活用英漢辭典</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>1248</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>e tu man di guo</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000584205</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>72586/Chinese (transliterated Pinyin without tones)</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Used For Term</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000250/AS-Academia Sinica</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000079740/AS-Academia Sinica data (2014-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>è tú màn dì guó</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000584206</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>72584/Chinese (transliterated Hanyu Pinyin)</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Used For Term</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000250/AS-Academia Sinica</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000079740/AS-Academia Sinica data (2014-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>e t'u man ti kuo</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000584207</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>72582/Chinese (transliterated Wade-Giles)</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Used For Term</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000250/AS-Academia Sinica</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000079740/AS-Academia Sinica data (2014-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>arte otomana</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000901522</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70543/Portuguese</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Singular Noun</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000316/CVAA-BR</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000109633/CVAA-BR Consortium (2020-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
    </Terms>
    <Associative_Relationships>
      <Associative_Relationship>
        <Relationship_Type>meaning/usage overlaps with</Relationship_Type>
        <Related_Subject_ID>
          <VP_Subject_ID>300193868</VP_Subject_ID>
        </Related_Subject_ID>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
      </Associative_Relationship>
    </Associative_Relationships>
    <Subject_Contributors>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000000/VP</Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000088/GCI</Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000131/CDBP-SNPC</Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000205/AAT-Ned</Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000250/AS-Academia Sinica</Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000316/CVAA-BR</Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
    </Subject_Contributors>
    <Subject_Sources>
      <Subject_Source>
        <Source>
          <Source_ID>2000051089/AATA database (2002-) </Source_ID>
        </Source>
      </Subject_Source>
      <Subject_Source>
        <Source>
          <Source_ID>2000035111/RIBA, Architectural Keywords (1982)</Source_ID>
        </Source>
      </Subject_Source>
      <Subject_Source>
        <Source>
          <Source_ID>2000035251/RILA, Subject Headings (1975-1990)</Source_ID>
        </Source>
      </Subject_Source>
      <Subject_Source>
        <Source>
          <Source_ID>2000052378/Winkler Prins Encyclopedie (1990)</Source_ID>
        </Source>
      </Subject_Source>
      <Subject_Source>
        <Source>
          <Source_ID>2000109633/CVAA-BR Consortium (2020-)</Source_ID>
        </Source>
      </Subject_Source>
    </Subject_Sources>
  </Subject>
</Vocabulary>