<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Vocabulary xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://vocabsservices.getty.edu/Schemas/AAT/AATGetSubject.xsd">
  <Subject Subject_ID="300198715">
    <Parent_Relationships>
      <Preferred_Parent>
        <Parent_Subject_ID>300107812</Parent_Subject_ID>
        <Relationship_Type>Parent/Child</Relationship_Type>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Parent_String>Colonial North American [300107812], Colonial American (pan-American style) [300018032], The Americas [300016617], styles, periods, and cultures by region [300111079], Styles and Periods (hierarchy name) [300015646], Styles and Periods Facet [300264088]</Parent_String>
        <Hier_Rel_Type>Genus/Species-BTG</Hier_Rel_Type>
      </Preferred_Parent>
    </Parent_Relationships>
    <Descriptive_Notes>
      <Descriptive_Note>
        <Note_Text>In general, the term usually refers to a culture or style produced by people who were born in the Americas or nearby islands, but who were descended from colonists or slaves, as distinguished from people who arrived directly from Europe or Africa, or who were descended from aboriginal populations. It is used to refer to the cultures of different populations in the context of different regions; its usage is often contradictory from region to region. It refers to the culture and styles produced by white people who had Spanish parents and were born in the Spanish territories of North and South America in the sixteenth through eighteenth centuries; their culture and social position were distinguished from residents who had been born in Spain. In modern usage in the context of Latin America, it may refer to the culture of people born locally but of pure Spanish extraction or specifically to traditions of old-line families of predominantly Spanish descent. The term may also refer to the culture of early South American blacks born in America, as distinguished from blacks brought directly from Africa. In Louisiana in the United States it refers to the culture of either French-speaking white descendants of early French and Spanish settlers or of mulattos speaking a form of French and Spanish patois.  It may also refer to the culture of people in the West Indies who were born and naturalized there, but were of Spanish, French, or African descent; in modern usage in the context of the Caribbean, it is often used to refer to Caribbean culture in general, including elements from European, African, Asian, and Amerindian sources.</Note_Text>
        <Note_Language>English</Note_Language>
        <Note_Contributors>
          <Note_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000000/VP</Contributor_id>
          </Note_Contributor>
        </Note_Contributors>
        <Note_Sources>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000099620/Legacy AAT data</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
        </Note_Sources>
      </Descriptive_Note>
      <Descriptive_Note>
        <Note_Text>El término refiere generalmente a una cultura o a un estilo producido por la gente que nació en las América o las islas próximas, estos fueron descendientes de colonos o de esclavos, se difieren de las personas que llegaron directamente de Europa o de África, o que la descendiente directa de poblaciones aborígenes. Se utiliza para referirse a las culturas de diversas poblaciones en el contexto de diversas regiones; su uso es a menudo contradictorio entre regiones. Refiérase también, a la cultura y a los estilos producidos por la gente blanca que tenía padres españoles y nacido en los territorios españoles del norte y Suramérica en los siglos XVI Y XVIII; su cultura y posición social eran distinguidas de los residentes que habían sido natos en España. En el contexto de América latina, puede referirse a la cultura local pero de extracción española pura o específicamente a las tradiciones familiares predominante española. El término puede también referir a la cultura de los negros de Norteamérica y llevados al sur de esta, distinguiéndolos de los negros traídos directamente de África. En Luisiana en los Estados Unidos refiere a la cultura de los descendientes blancos francófonos de colonos franceses y españoles o de los mulatos que hablan una forma de lengua francesa y española. Puede también referirse a la cultura de la gente en Indias del oeste que fueron llevadas y naturalizadas allí, pero estaban dependiente de los españoles, franceses, o africanos. En el contexto del Caribe, es de uso frecuente referirse a esta cultura generalmente incluyendo elementos de fuentes europeas, africanas, asiáticas, y de América indiana.</Note_Text>
        <Note_Language>Spanish</Note_Language>
        <Note_Contributors>
          <Note_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000131/CDBP-SNPC</Contributor_id>
          </Note_Contributor>
        </Note_Contributors>
        <Note_Sources>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000051034/TAA database (2000-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
        </Note_Sources>
      </Descriptive_Note>
      <Descriptive_Note>
        <Note_Text>In algemene zin verwijst de term meestal naar een cultuur of stijl welke is geproduceerd door mensen die in Noord- of Zuid-Amerika of op de nabijgelegen eilanden geboren zijn, maar die afstammen van kolonisten of slaven, ter onderscheiding van mensen die rechtstreeks uit Europa of Afrika kwamen of die van oorspronkelijke bevolkingsgroepen afstammen. De term verwijst naar de culturen van verschillende bevolkingsgroepen binnen de context van verschillende regio's; vaak verschilt de betekenis van de term per regio en worden daarbij zelfs tegenstrijdige betekenissen gezien. De term verwijst naar de cultuur en stijlen geproduceerd door blanken met Spaanse ouders die in de periode van de 16de tot en met de 18de eeuw in de Spaanse gebieden in Noord- en Zuid-Amerika werden geboren; ze hadden een andere cultuur en maatschappelijke positie dan bewoners die in Spanje waren geboren. In het moderne taalgebruik kan de term binnen de context van Latijns-Amerika verwijzen naar de cultuur van mensen die daar wel geboren zijn maar van wie beide ouders Spaans zijn, of in specifieke zin naar de tradities van oude families met een overwegend Spaanse achtergrond. Ook kan de term verwijzen naar de cultuur van vroege Zuid-Amerikaanse zwarten die in Amerika zijn geboren, ter onderscheiding van zwarten die rechtstreeks uit Afrika waren overgebracht. In Louisiana, in de Verenigde Staten, verwijst de term naar de cultuur van Franstalige blanke afstammelingen van vroege Franse en Spaanse kolonisten, of naar mulatten die een soort Frans-Spaanse mengtaal spreken. Daarnaast kan de term verwijzen naar de cultuur van mensen op de West-Indische eilanden die daar zijn geboren en genaturaliseerd, maar van Spaanse, Franse of Afrikaanse afkomst zijn; in het moderne taalgebruik, binnen de context van het Caribisch gebied, verwijst de term vaak naar de Caribische cultuur in het algemeen, met inbegrip van oorspronkelijk Europese, Afrikaanse, Aziatische en Amerikaans-Indiaanse elementen.</Note_Text>
        <Note_Language>Dutch</Note_Language>
        <Note_Contributors>
          <Note_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000205/AAT-Ned</Contributor_id>
          </Note_Contributor>
        </Note_Contributors>
        <Note_Sources>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000113770/AAT-Ned (1994-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
        </Note_Sources>
      </Descriptive_Note>
      <Descriptive_Note>
        <Note_Text>該詞彙普遍用來描述出生於美洲或鄰近島嶼之殖民拓荒者的後裔，或奴隸的後裔之風格與文化，用以區別直接來自歐洲或非洲的人，或是當地原住民的後代。該詞彙用來指稱不同區域脈絡中不同族群的文化；各個地區對於這個詞彙的用法通常是互相矛盾的。在十六到十八世紀時，這個詞彙用來描述具有西班牙血統的雙親，且出生於北美洲與南美洲的西班牙領地的白人文化與風格；他們的文化與社會地位均不同於出生於西班牙的當地居民。在拉丁美洲脈絡中，這個詞彙在當代被用來描述出生於本地，但具有純正西班牙血統的人的文化，或特別是指具有悠久歷史，且有領導地位之西班牙家族後裔的傳統。這個詞彙也用來指稱早期出生在美洲的黑人所產生的南美洲黑人文化，以區別直接從非洲被帶來美洲的黑人。在美國路易斯安納州（Louisiana），這個詞彙被用來描述使用法語的早期法國或西班牙殖民者白人後裔之所屬文化，或是用來描述使用近似法文和西班牙方言的黑白混血兒所屬文化。該詞彙也被用來指涉出生於西印度群島，但已經完全適應當地之西班牙人、法國人與非洲人後裔的所屬文化；在加勒比文化脈絡中，這個詞彙在當代通常泛指加勒比文化，包括了來自歐洲、非洲、亞洲與美洲印第安之文化元素。</Note_Text>
        <Note_Language>Chinese (traditional)</Note_Language>
        <Note_Contributors>
          <Note_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000250/AS-Academia Sinica</Contributor_id>
          </Note_Contributor>
        </Note_Contributors>
        <Note_Sources>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000052784/TELDAP database (2009-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
        </Note_Sources>
      </Descriptive_Note>
      <Descriptive_Note>
        <Note_Text>Généralement, le terme fait référence à une culture ou à un style produit par des personnes nées aux Amériques ou dans les îles voisines, mais dont les ancêtres étaient des colons ou des esclaves, à la différence des individus arrivés directement d’Europe ou d’Afrique, ou qui descendaient des populations aborigènes. Ce terme est utilisé pour désigner les cultures de différentes catégories de population dans le contexte de différentes régions ; son usage est donc souvent discordant d’une région à l’autre. Il renvoie à la culture et aux styles produits par les Blancs de parents espagnols nés dans les territoires espagnols d’Amérique du Nord et du Sud du 16e au 18e siècle ; leur culture et leur position sociale étaient très différentes des personnes nées en Espagne. Aujourd’hui, dans le contexte de l’Amérique latine, le terme peut désigner la culture des individus nés sur place, mais de pure extraction espagnole ou, plus spécifiquement, les traditions de vieilles familles principalement d’origine espagnole. Le terme peut également faire référence à la culture des premiers Noirs sud-américains nés en Amérique, par opposition aux Noirs originaires d’Afrique. Dans la Louisiane aux États-Unis, il se réfère à la culture, soit des descendants blancs francophones des premiers colons français et espagnols, soit des mulâtres qui parlent une forme de patois français et espagnol. Le terme peut également indiquer la culture des personnes nées et naturalisées aux Antilles, mais ayant des origines espagnoles, françaises ou africaines. Dans son usage moderne dans le contexte des Caraïbes, le terme est fréquemment utilisé pour désigner la culture caribéenne au sens large, comprenant des éléments de sources européennes, africaines, asiatiques et amérindiennes.</Note_Text>
        <Note_Language>French</Note_Language>
        <Note_Contributors>
          <Note_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000305/BEINFRAT </Contributor_id>
          </Note_Contributor>
        </Note_Contributors>
        <Note_Sources>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000115330/BEINFRAT-network (2022)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
        </Note_Sources>
      </Descriptive_Note>
    </Descriptive_Notes>
    <Record_Type>Concept</Record_Type>
    <Merged_Status>Merged</Merged_Status>
    <Sort_Order>1</Sort_Order>
    <Terms>
      <Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>Creole</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000198715</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70051/English</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>North American culture</Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Adjectival</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000000/VP</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000088/GCI</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000046657/Avery Index (1963-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>subheading</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000048328/Contributed as a candidate term</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>UCBerk - 9/91</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000022191/Edwards, Louisiana's Remarkable French Vernacular Architecture (1988)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>illustration, 2</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000046682/Random House Dictionary of the English Language (1987)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000051089/AATA database (2002-) </Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>122451 checked 26 January 2012</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>Criollo</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000272705</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70641/Spanish</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70051/English</Language>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Used For Term</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000131/CDBP-SNPC</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000000/VP</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000051034/TAA database (2000-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000093795/Encyclopedia Britannica Online (2002-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>"Creole." Accessed 02/26/2001.</Page>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>Créole</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000272706</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70051/English</Language>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>North American culture</Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Used For Term</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000000/VP</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000093795/Encyclopedia Britannica Online (2002-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>"Creole." Accessed 02/26/2001.</Page>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>creools</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000498882</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70261/Dutch</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000205/AAT-Ned</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000113770/AAT-Ned (1994-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>克里奧爾</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000559659</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>72551/Chinese (traditional)</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000250/AS-Academia Sinica</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000093495/大英百科全書線上繁體中文版</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>August 7, 2012</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>kè lǐ ào ěr</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000559662</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>72584/Chinese (transliterated Hanyu Pinyin)</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Used For Term</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000250/AS-Academia Sinica</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000052784/TELDAP database (2009-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>ke li ao er</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000559661</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>72586/Chinese (transliterated Pinyin without tones)</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Used For Term</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000250/AS-Academia Sinica</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000052784/TELDAP database (2009-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>k'o li ao erh</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000559663</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>72582/Chinese (transliterated Wade-Giles)</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Used For Term</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000250/AS-Academia Sinica</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000052784/TELDAP database (2009-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>克里奧耳</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000559660</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>72551/Chinese (traditional)</Language>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Used For Term</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000250/AS-Academia Sinica</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000070458/智慧藏百科全書網</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>August 7, 2012</Page>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>créoles</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000896066</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70271/French</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Plural Noun</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000305/BEINFRAT </Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000115330/BEINFRAT-network (2022)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>créole</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000896067</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70271/French</Language>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Alternate Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Singular Noun</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000305/BEINFRAT </Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000115330/BEINFRAT-network (2022)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
    </Terms>
    <Subject_Contributors>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000088/GCI</Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000000/VP</Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000205/AAT-Ned</Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000131/CDBP-SNPC</Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000250/AS-Academia Sinica</Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000305/BEINFRAT </Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
    </Subject_Contributors>
    <Subject_Sources>
      <Subject_Source>
        <Source>
          <Source_ID>2000051089/AATA database (2002-) </Source_ID>
        </Source>
      </Subject_Source>
      <Subject_Source>
        <Source>
          <Source_ID>2000046657/Avery Index (1963-)</Source_ID>
        </Source>
      </Subject_Source>
      <Subject_Source>
        <Source>
          <Source_ID>2000014591/Fairbanks and Bates, American Furniture (1981)</Source_ID>
        </Source>
      </Subject_Source>
      <Subject_Source>
        <Source>
          <Source_ID>2000024811/CDMARC Subjects: LCSH (1988-)</Source_ID>
        </Source>
      </Subject_Source>
      <Subject_Source>
        <Source>
          <Source_ID>2000077471/Sturgis, Dictionary of Architecture and Building (1901)</Source_ID>
        </Source>
      </Subject_Source>
      <Subject_Source>
        <Source>
          <Source_ID>2000113770/AAT-Ned (1994-)</Source_ID>
        </Source>
      </Subject_Source>
      <Subject_Source>
        <Source>
          <Source_ID>2000115330/BEINFRAT-network (2022)</Source_ID>
        </Source>
      </Subject_Source>
    </Subject_Sources>
  </Subject>
</Vocabulary>