<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Vocabulary xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://vocabsservices.getty.edu/Schemas/AAT/AATGetSubject.xsd">
  <Subject Subject_ID="300264513">
    <Parent_Relationships>
      <Preferred_Parent>
        <Parent_Subject_ID>300220519</Parent_Subject_ID>
        <Relationship_Type>Parent/Child</Relationship_Type>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Parent_String>religious texts [300220519], documents by function [300137955], document genres [300026031], information forms (objects) [300220751], Information Forms (hierarchy name) [300026029], Visual and Verbal Communication (hierarchy name) [300264552], Objects Facet [300264092]</Parent_String>
        <Hier_Rel_Type>Genus/Species-BTG</Hier_Rel_Type>
      </Preferred_Parent>
    </Parent_Relationships>
    <Descriptive_Notes>
      <Descriptive_Note>
        <Note_Text>Refers to books, scrolls, rolls, or other document forms containing the sacred scriptures of Judaism or Christianity. Bibles may also contain illuminations, which are painted scenes or decorations. The Bible is composed of two parts: The Hebrew scriptures or Old Testament, written originally in Hebrew (with some parts in Aramaic) and including the writings of the Jewish people, and the New Testament, composed in Greek and recording the story of Jesus and the beginnings of Christianity. The Roman Catholic and Eastern Orthodox versions of the Old Testament are somewhat larger than the Protestant Bible because they accept certain books and parts of books considered apocryphal by Protestants. The Jewish Bible includes only the books known to Christians as the Old Testament. The arrangements of the Jewish and Christian canons differ considerably. Traditionally the Jews have divided their scriptures (the Old Testament) into three parts: The Torah (the "Law"), or Pentateuch; the Nevi'im (the "Prophets"); and the Ketuvim (the "Writings"), or Hagiographa. The stories, moral teachings, and theological doctrines in the bible have provided subjects for an immense body of visual art in both Christian and Jewish imagery. For Christians, a canon of biblical books was established in the Early Christian period; however, several apocryphal books continued to circulate long afterwards. Beginning in the late medieval period, poetic and dramatic interpretations of biblical narratives were very popular, providing ample extra-canonical literature that contributed to the development of important subjects in Christian art.</Note_Text>
        <Note_Language>English</Note_Language>
        <Note_Contributors>
          <Note_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000000/VP</Contributor_id>
          </Note_Contributor>
        </Note_Contributors>
        <Note_Sources>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000093795/Encyclopedia Britannica Online (2002-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000045262/Grove Dictionary of Art online (1999-2002)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
        </Note_Sources>
      </Descriptive_Note>
      <Descriptive_Note>
        <Note_Text>Se refiere a libros, pergaminos, rollos y otras formas de documento que contienen escrituras sagradas del judaísmo o cristianismo. Las biblias pueden contener iluminaciones, que son escenas o decoraciones pintadas. La Biblia se compone de dos partes: Las Escrituras Hebreas o Viejo Testamento, originalmente escritos en hebreo (con alguna partes en arameo) e incluye las escrituras el pueblo hebreo; y el Nuevo Testamento, escrito en griego y relata la historia de Jesús y de los inicios del cristianismo. Las versiones del Antiguo Testamento del catolicismo romano y ortodoxo oriental, son algo más extensas que la Biblia Protestante debido a que los primeros aceptan ciertos libros y partes de libros considerados apócritos por los protestantes. La Biblia judía sólo incluye los libros conocidos por los cristianos como Antiguo Testamento. La adaptación de cánones judíos y cristianos difiere considerablemente. Tradicionalmente, los judíos han dividido sus escrituras (Antiguo Testamento) en tres partes: La Torá (la "Ley") o Pentateuco; el Nevi'm (los "Profestas") y el Ketuvim (las "Escrituras") o Hagiografías. Las historias, enseñanzas morales y doctrinas teológicas en la biblia, han provisto de temas para un gran cuerpo de arte visual, tanto para la imaginería cristiana como la judía. Para los cristianos, un canon de libro bíblico fue establecido durante el periodo del cristianismo temprano, sin embargo, varios libros apócrifos continuaron circulando por mucho tiempo. En los inicios del periodo medieval tardío eran muy populares las interpretaciones poéticas y dramáticas de narraciones bíblicas, proporcionando una gran cantidad de literatura extra-canónica que contribuyó a desarrollar importantes temas para el arte cristiano.</Note_Text>
        <Note_Language>Spanish</Note_Language>
        <Note_Contributors>
          <Note_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000131/CDBP-SNPC</Contributor_id>
          </Note_Contributor>
        </Note_Contributors>
        <Note_Sources>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000051034/TAA database (2000-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
        </Note_Sources>
      </Descriptive_Note>
      <Descriptive_Note>
        <Note_Text>Verwijst naar boeken, perkamentrollen, schriftrollen of andere documentvormen die de heilige geschriften van het jodendom of het christendom bevatten. Bijbels kunnen daarnaast verluchtingen bevatten in de vorm van geschilderde scènes of decoraties. De Bijbel bestaat uit twee delen: de Hebreeuwse geschriften oftewel het Oude Testament, oorspronkelijk geschreven in het Hebreeuws (met enkele delen in het Aramees) inclusief de geschriften van het joodse volk, en het Nieuwe Testament, in het Grieks geschreven, waarin het verhaal van Jezus en de oorsprong van het christendom zijn opgetekend. De rooms-katholieke en oosters-orthodoxe versies van het Oude Testament zijn uitgebreider dan die van de protestantse bijbel, aangezien zij bepaalde boeken en delen van boeken accepteren die door de protestanten als apocrief worden beschouwd. De joodse Bijbel omvat alleen de boeken die de christenen kennen als het Oude Testament. De indeling van het joodse en christelijke canon toont grote verschillen. Van oudsher hebben de joden hun geschriften (het Oude Testament) in drie delen verdeeld: de Thora (de 'Wet') of Pentateuch; de Nevi'im (de 'Profeten'); en de Ketuvim (de 'Geschriften') of Hagiographa. De verhalen, de zedenleer en de theologische doctrines in de Bijbel leverden stof voor een immense hoeveelheid kunstwerken die zowel christelijke als joodse thema's verbeelden. Voor de christenen werd de canon van Bijbelboeken in de vroegchristelijke periode vastgelegd; ook nog lang daarna bleven er echter diverse apocriefe geschriften circuleren. Vanaf de late middeleeuwen genoten poëtische en dramatische interpretaties van Bijbelverhalen grote populariteit, wat aanleiding gaf tot een overvloed aan buitencanonieke literatuur die bijdroeg tot belangrijke thema's in de christelijke kunst.</Note_Text>
        <Note_Language>Dutch</Note_Language>
        <Note_Contributors>
          <Note_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000205/AAT-Ned</Contributor_id>
          </Note_Contributor>
        </Note_Contributors>
        <Note_Sources>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000113770/AAT-Ned (1994-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
        </Note_Sources>
      </Descriptive_Note>
      <Descriptive_Note>
        <Note_Text>指包含猶太或基督教聖經經文的書籍、卷軸以及書冊。聖經也可包含經文註釋，如場景圖繪或裝飾。聖經由兩個部份組成：希伯來文聖經讀本或舊約，原文以希伯來文撰寫（有些則為阿拉姆語），也包括猶太人事蹟的書寫、以及原文為希臘文的新約，其中記載了耶穌的故事以及基督教的源起。羅馬天主教及東正教的舊約版本在內容上較基督教聖經為多，因為另外編入其他書籍或被基督教視為作者不明之書。而猶太聖經則只包含基督教所認識的舊約。猶太教與基督教在教規上有極大的不同。傳統猶太教將聖經（舊約）分成三個部份：摩西五經（法律書）、先知書以及聖書。其中的故事、教導以及神學教誨對有關基督教與猶太教意象上的藝術提供了許多題材。對於基督徒而言，聖經書籍的教規於基督教發展早期已經成形，但有些不知名的書籍在其後仍繼續流傳許久。中古時代初期，對聖經經文的描述、詩歌與戲劇性的詮釋極其流行，提供豐富的聖經典外的文學，並對基督教藝術產生極大的影響與貢獻。</Note_Text>
        <Note_Language>Chinese (traditional)</Note_Language>
        <Note_Contributors>
          <Note_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000250/AS-Academia Sinica</Contributor_id>
          </Note_Contributor>
        </Note_Contributors>
        <Note_Sources>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000079740/AS-Academia Sinica data (2014-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
        </Note_Sources>
      </Descriptive_Note>
      <Descriptive_Note>
        <Note_Text>Bezieht sich auf ein Buch, eine Schriftrolle oder andere Dokumentform, die die heiligen Schriften des Judentums oder des Christentums enthält. Eine Bibel kann auch Buchmalerei, gemalte Szenen oder Verzierungen enthalten. Die Bibel besteht aus zwei Teilen: die hebräischen Schriften oder das Alte Testament,  das ursprünglich auf Hebräisch (mit einigen Teilen von Aramäisch) verfasst wurde und die Schriften des jüdischen Volks enthält, und das Neue Testament, das auf Griechisch verfasst wurde und die Geschichte Jesu und die Anfänge des Christentums aufzeichnet. Die römisch-katholische und die östlich-orthodoxe Version des Alten Testaments sind etwas umfangreicher als die protestantische Bibel, weil sie bestimmte Bücher und Teile von Büchern akzeptieren, die von den Protestanten als apokryph angesehen werden. Die jüdische Bibel enthält nur die Bücher, die den Christen als Altes Testament bekannt sind. Die Gestaltung des jüdischen und des christlichen Kanons unterscheiden sich erheblich. Traditionell haben die Juden ihre Schriften (das Alte Testament) in drei Teile geteilt: die Tora (das "Gesetz") oder das Pentateuch; die Neviim (die "Propheten"); und die Ketuvim (die "Schriften") oder die Hagiographen. Die Geschichten, moralischen Lehren und theologischen Doktrinen der Bibel haben sowohl in der christlichen als auch in der jüdischen Bildsprache ein umfangreiches Werk der bildenden Kunst hervorgebracht. Für die Christen wurde in der frühchristlichen Zeit ein Kanon biblischer Bücher festgelegt; einige apokryphe Bücher waren jedoch noch lange danach im Umlauf. Ab dem späten Mittelalter waren poetische und dramatische Interpretationen der biblischen Erzählungen sehr beliebt und lieferten eine Fülle außerkanonischer Literatur, die zur Entwicklung wichtiger Themen in der christlichen Kunst beitrug.</Note_Text>
        <Note_Language>German</Note_Language>
        <Note_Contributors>
          <Note_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000232/IfM-SMB-PK</Contributor_id>
          </Note_Contributor>
        </Note_Contributors>
        <Note_Sources>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000122134/IfM Berlin</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
        </Note_Sources>
      </Descriptive_Note>
    </Descriptive_Notes>
    <Record_Type>Concept</Record_Type>
    <Merged_Status>Merged</Merged_Status>
    <Sort_Order>1</Sort_Order>
    <Terms>
      <Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>Bibles</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000303672</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70051/English</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Singular Noun</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000000/VP</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000045262/Grove Dictionary of Art online (1999-2002)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>Bible</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000303671</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70051/English</Language>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Alternate Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Plural Noun</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000000/VP</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000088/GCI</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000093795/Encyclopedia Britannica Online (2002-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>"'Bible." Accessed 01/15/2002.</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000045262/Grove Dictionary of Art online (1999-2002)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>"Bible," accessed 06/11/2001.</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000046693/Merriam-Webster's Collegiate Dictionary [online] (1997-2002)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>cccessed 11 June 2001</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000046986/Webster's Third New International Dictionary (1986)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000046682/Random House Dictionary of the English Language (1987)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000114707/Oxford English Dictionary Online (2002-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>accessed 23 May 2005</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000051089/AATA database (2002-) </Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>120989 checked 26 January 2012</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>bibles</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000307884</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70051/English</Language>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Used For Term</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Noun</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000000/VP</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000046986/Webster's Third New International Dictionary (1986)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>biblias</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000456979</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70641/Spanish</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Plural Noun</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000131/CDBP-SNPC</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000051214/Comité, Plural del término en singular</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>biblia</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000456980</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70641/Spanish</Language>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Alternate Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Singular Noun</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000131/CDBP-SNPC</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000048810/Moliner, Diccionario de uso del español (2004)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>I:372</Page>
            <Preferred>Unknown</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000051228/Fatás y Borrás, Diccionario de términos de Arte y elementos de Arqueología, Heráldica y Numismática (1997)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>41</Page>
            <Preferred>Unknown</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>Bijbel</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000512865</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70261/Dutch</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000205/AAT-Ned</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000113770/AAT-Ned (1994-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>Bijbels</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000512866</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70261/Dutch</Language>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Alternate Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000205/AAT-Ned</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000113770/AAT-Ned (1994-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Unknown</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>bible</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000781419</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70271/French</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Alternate Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>feminine singular noun</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70051/English</Language>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Alternate Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Singular Noun</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000159/CHIN / RCIP</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000299/AASLH</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000298/IMJ</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000106160/Nomenclature database (2018-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>http://nomenclature.info/nom/13235; scheme: Nomenclature-Objects</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000106165/AASLH data (2016-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000106166/Nomenclature for Museum Cataloging / Nomenclature pour le catalogage translation project (2016-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>13235</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000106167/CHIN / RCIP translation (2016-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000109720/Israel Museum Jerusalem contribution (n.d.)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>תנ"ך</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000846383</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>73170/Hebrew</Language>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Noun</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>
            </Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000298/IMJ</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000109720/Israel Museum Jerusalem contribution (n.d.)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Unknown</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>ספר תנ"ך</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000846384</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>73170/Hebrew</Language>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Used For Term</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Noun</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>
            </Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000298/IMJ</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000109720/Israel Museum Jerusalem contribution (n.d.)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Unknown</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>聖經</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000856277</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>72551/Chinese (traditional)</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000250/AS-Academia Sinica</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000112091/朗文當代大辭典</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>147</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000112092/國家教育研究院－雙語詞彙、學術名詞暨辭書資訊網</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>December 26, 2014</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000112093/智慧藏百科全書網</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>December 26, 2014</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000112094/牛津當代大辭典</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>153</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000112095/大英百科全書線上繁體中文版</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>December 26, 2014</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>sheng ching</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000856280</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>72582/Chinese (transliterated Wade-Giles)</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Used For Term</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000250/AS-Academia Sinica</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000079740/AS-Academia Sinica data (2014-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>sheng jing</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000856278</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>72586/Chinese (transliterated Pinyin without tones)</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Used For Term</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000250/AS-Academia Sinica</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000079740/AS-Academia Sinica data (2014-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>shèng jīng</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000856279</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>72584/Chinese (transliterated Hanyu Pinyin)</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Used For Term</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000250/AS-Academia Sinica</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000079740/AS-Academia Sinica data (2014-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>Bibel</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Vernacular</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000912348</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70101/German</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Singular Noun</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>
            </Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000232/IfM-SMB-PK</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000083634/Duden [online] (2011-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>https://www.duden.de/node/22218/revision/612284</Page>
            <Preferred>Unknown</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000083630/GND - Gemeinsame Normdatei</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>https://d-nb.info/gnd/4006406-2</Page>
            <Preferred>Unknown</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000120577/Jakobi-Mirwald, Das mittelalterliche Buch (2004)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>298</Page>
            <Preferred>Unknown</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000085514/Benz, Glossarium Artis 2 (1992)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>96</Page>
            <Preferred>Unknown</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>Bibeln</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Vernacular</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000912349</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70101/German</Language>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Alternate Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Plural Noun</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>
            </Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000232/IfM-SMB-PK</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000083634/Duden [online] (2011-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>https://www.duden.de/node/22218/revision/612284</Page>
            <Preferred>Unknown</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
    </Terms>
    <Associative_Relationships>
      <Associative_Relationship>
        <Relationship_Type>basis of</Relationship_Type>
        <Related_Subject_ID>
          <VP_Subject_ID>300263184</VP_Subject_ID>
        </Related_Subject_ID>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
      </Associative_Relationship>
      <Associative_Relationship>
        <Relationship_Type>basis of</Relationship_Type>
        <Related_Subject_ID>
          <VP_Subject_ID>300211640</VP_Subject_ID>
        </Related_Subject_ID>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
      </Associative_Relationship>
      <Associative_Relationship>
        <Relationship_Type>reflect/produced by</Relationship_Type>
        <Related_Subject_ID>
          <VP_Subject_ID>300073711</VP_Subject_ID>
        </Related_Subject_ID>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
      </Associative_Relationship>
      <Associative_Relationship>
        <Relationship_Type>reflect/produced by</Relationship_Type>
        <Related_Subject_ID>
          <VP_Subject_ID>300073723</VP_Subject_ID>
        </Related_Subject_ID>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
      </Associative_Relationship>
    </Associative_Relationships>
    <Subject_Contributors>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000000/VP</Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000088/GCI</Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000131/CDBP-SNPC</Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000205/AAT-Ned</Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000159/CHIN / RCIP</Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000299/AASLH</Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000298/IMJ</Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000250/AS-Academia Sinica</Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000232/IfM-SMB-PK</Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
    </Subject_Contributors>
    <Subject_Sources>
      <Subject_Source>
        <Source>
          <Source_ID>2000051089/AATA database (2002-) </Source_ID>
        </Source>
      </Subject_Source>
      <Subject_Source>
        <Source>
          <Source_ID>2000113770/AAT-Ned (1994-)</Source_ID>
        </Source>
      </Subject_Source>
      <Subject_Source>
        <Source>
          <Source_ID>2000106160/Nomenclature database (2018-)</Source_ID>
        </Source>
      </Subject_Source>
      <Subject_Source>
        <Source>
          <Source_ID>2000106165/AASLH data (2016-)</Source_ID>
        </Source>
      </Subject_Source>
      <Subject_Source>
        <Source>
          <Source_ID>2000106166/Nomenclature for Museum Cataloging / Nomenclature pour le catalogage translation project (2016-)</Source_ID>
        </Source>
      </Subject_Source>
      <Subject_Source>
        <Source>
          <Source_ID>2000106167/CHIN / RCIP translation (2016-)</Source_ID>
        </Source>
      </Subject_Source>
      <Subject_Source>
        <Source>
          <Source_ID>2000109720/Israel Museum Jerusalem contribution (n.d.)</Source_ID>
        </Source>
      </Subject_Source>
    </Subject_Sources>
  </Subject>
</Vocabulary>