<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Vocabulary xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://vocabsservices.getty.edu/Schemas/AAT/AATGetSubject.xsd">
  <Subject Subject_ID="300264544">
    <Parent_Relationships>
      <Preferred_Parent>
        <Parent_Subject_ID>300073708</Parent_Subject_ID>
        <Relationship_Type>Parent/Child</Relationship_Type>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Parent_String>religions (belief systems, cultures) [300073708], religions and religious concepts [300055980], Associated Concepts (hierarchy name) [300055126], Associated Concepts Facet [300264086]</Parent_String>
        <Hier_Rel_Type>Genus/Species-BTG</Hier_Rel_Type>
      </Preferred_Parent>
    </Parent_Relationships>
    <Descriptive_Notes>
      <Descriptive_Note>
        <Note_Text>Refers to an indigenous religion of Tibet that is, along with Buddhism, one of the two main religions of the country. Many aspects of Bon were mixed with the Buddhist traditions introduced from India in the 8th century and gave Tibetan Buddhism much of its distinctiveness. Disagreement amongst the ruling class of Tibet in the 8th and 9th centuries resulted in the noble families choosing Bon and the ruling house choosing Buddhism. The religion became organized around the 11th century largely thanks to the Buddhist concern for written works. Besides surviving in many aspects of Tibetan Buddhism, Bon continues to thrive in the northern and eastern frontiers of Tibet. It is unclear how much continuity there is between ancient and modern Bon. The features of ancient Bon are hard to determine because all early description are Buddhist and what is known of Bon today is heavily influenced by Mahayana Buddhism. Ancient Bon seems to have featured animism, shamanism, and the practice of magic rites. The Bon gods of the atmosphere, the earth, and subterranean regions were incorporated into the Buddhist pantheon as lesser deities. There is evidence of a cult of divine kingship in which the kings are seen as manifestations of the sky divinity; this belief may be the root of the reincarnated lamas of Buddhism. Bon oracular priests have as their counterpart the Buddhist soothsayers. Aspects of Bon doctrine are virtually identical to that of Tibetan Buddhism, including doctrine of buddhahood and the bodhisattva ideal. Particularly noteworthy are the dzogchen beliefs of Bon that are shared with the Nyingma school of Tibetan Buddhism; these beliefs hold that there is an ineffable state beyond all Buddhas and all manifestation. The Bon monastic system is also almost identical to that of the Geluk school. Nevertheless, believers in Bon rigorously guard their non-Buddhist image. Shenrab is considered the founder of the religion and the historical Buddha Shakyamuni is said to be a manifestation of him. Bon scriptures are of one of two groups: the 'Kanjur,' containing myths, doctrines, and biographies of Shenrab; and 'Katen,' containing commentary and ritual and iconographic works. The name Tibet is derived from Bon.</Note_Text>
        <Note_Language>English</Note_Language>
        <Note_Contributors>
          <Note_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000000/VP</Contributor_id>
          </Note_Contributor>
        </Note_Contributors>
        <Note_Sources>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000045248/Bowker, Oxford Dictionary of World Religions (1997)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000046363/Encyclopedia Britannica Online (1994-2001)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000045789/Goring, ed., Larousse Dictionary of Beliefs and Religions (1994)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000093795/Encyclopedia Britannica Online (2002-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
        </Note_Sources>
      </Descriptive_Note>
      <Descriptive_Note>
        <Note_Text>Se refiere a una religión indígena del Tibet que es, junto con el Budismo, una de las dos religiones principales del país. Muchos aspectos del Bon fueron mezclados con las tradiciones budistas introducidas desde India en el siglo VIII, dieron al Budismo Tibetano muchas de sus características. Desavenencias entre la clase gobernante del Tibet en los siglos VIII y IX terminaron con las familias nobles escogiendo a Bon y la casa gobernante eligiendo el Budismo. La religión se organizó en gran parte alrededor del siglo XI gracias a la preocupación budista por los trabajos escritos. Además de mantener muchos aspectos del Budismo Tibetano, Bon continúa creciendo en las fronteras norteñas y orientales del Tibet. Es incierto cuánta continuidad hay entre el Bon antiguo y el moderno. Las características del Bon antiguo son difíciles de determinar porque toda la descripción temprana es budista y lo que es conocido de Bon hoy está fuertemente influenciado por el Budismo Mahayana. El antiguo Bon parece haber ofrecido el animismo, shamanismo y la práctica de ritos mágicos. Los dioses de Bon de la atmósfera, la tierra, y las regiones subterráneas estaban incorporados en el panteón budista como deidades menores. Hay evidencia de un culto de monarquía divina en el que los reyes se ven como manifestaciones de la divinidad del cielo; esta creencia puede ser la raíz de los lamas reencarnados del Budismo. Los sacerdotes del árculo Bon tienen como su contraparte los clarividentes budistas. Los aspectos de la doctrina Bon son casi idénticos a los del Budismo Tibetano, incluyendo la doctrina de la Gran Iluminación.</Note_Text>
        <Note_Language>Spanish</Note_Language>
        <Note_Contributors>
          <Note_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000131/CDBP-SNPC</Contributor_id>
          </Note_Contributor>
        </Note_Contributors>
        <Note_Sources>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000051034/TAA database (2000-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
        </Note_Sources>
      </Descriptive_Note>
      <Descriptive_Note>
        <Note_Text>Verwijst naar een inheemse Tibetaanse godsdienst die met het boeddhisme een van de twee voornaamste religies van het land is. Veel aspecten van Bon raakten vermengd met de boeddhistische tradities die in de 8ste eeuw werden ingevoerd uit India en die het Tibetaanse boeddhisme veel van zijn eigenheid hebben verleend. Onenigheid binnen de heersende klasse van Tibet leidde er in de 8ste en 9de eeuw toe dat de adellijke families voor Bon kozen en de heersende dynastie voor het boeddhisme. Bon werd rond de 11de eeuw een georganiseerde godsdienst, vooral dankzij de boeddhistische belangstelling voor geschreven teksten. Bon leeft voort in veel aspecten van het Tibetaanse boeddhisme en is bovendien nog altijd een bloeiende godsdienst in de noordelijke en oostelijke grensgebieden van Tibet. Onduidelijk is hoeveel continuïteit er bestaat tussen het oude en het moderne Bon. De kenmerken van het oude Bon zijn moeilijk vast te stellen omdat alle vroege beschrijvingen boeddhistisch zijn. Alles wat tegenwoordig over Bon bekend is, is zwaar beïnvloed door het Mahayana-boeddhisme. Het oude Bon lijkt elementen van animisme, sjamanisme en de uitoefening van magische riten te hebben bevat. De Bon-goden van lucht, aarde en zee werden als lagere goden in het boeddhistische pantheon opgenomen. Er zijn aanwijzingen voor een cultus van heilig koningschap waarin de koningen worden beschouwd als manifestaties van de luchtgod; dit geloof zou de oorsprong kunnen zijn van de gereïncarneerde lama’s van het boeddhisme. De orakelpriesters van Bon hebben hun tegenhangers in de boeddhistische waarzeggers. Bepaalde aspecten van de Bon-doctrine zijn vrijwel identiek aan die van het Tibetaanse boeddhisme, zoals de leer van het boeddhaschap en het ideaal van bodhisattva. Opvallend zijn de dzogchen-overtuigingen die het Bon deelt met de Nyingma-school van het Tibetaanse boeddhisme; zij houden in dat er een onuitsprekelijke toestand bestaat, voorbij alle boeddha’s en alle verschijningen. Verder is het kloostersysteem van Bon bijna gelijk aan dat van de Gelug-school. Toch bewaken de Bon-gelovigen nauwgezet hun niet-boeddhistische imago. Shenrab wordt beschouwd als de stichter van de godsdienst en de historische Boeddha Shakyamuni zou een manifestatie van hem zijn. Bon-geschriften zijn verdeeld in twee groepen: de Kanjur, met mythen, doctrines en biografieën van Shenrab, en de Katen, die commentaren en rituele en iconografische werken omvat. De naam Tibet komt uit de Bon-religie.</Note_Text>
        <Note_Language>Dutch</Note_Language>
        <Note_Contributors>
          <Note_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000205/AAT-Ned</Contributor_id>
          </Note_Contributor>
        </Note_Contributors>
        <Note_Sources>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000113770/AAT-Ned (1994-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
        </Note_Sources>
      </Descriptive_Note>
      <Descriptive_Note>
        <Note_Text>西藏本土宗教，與佛教同為西藏的兩大宗教。西元八世紀從印度傳入的佛教傳統混合部分苯教內容，使藏傳佛教具有其獨特性。西元八世紀及九世紀時，西藏統治階層意見不合，導致貴族信奉苯教，而王室則支持佛教。約於西元十一世紀時，拜佛教徒對佛教經典著作的重視所賜，使得苯教變得更為組織化。除了藏傳佛教諸多方面吸收了苯教內容，苯教也持續興盛於西藏北部及東部邊境。至今尚不清楚古代苯教與現代苯教之間有多少延續性。由於早期的敘述皆與佛教有關，因而古代苯教的特徵很難界定，而如今為人所知的苯教則受到大乘佛教很大的影響。古代苯教特徵包括相信萬物有靈、巫醫論，以及巫術儀式的施行。苯教的氣神、土神，以及地下世界的神被併入佛教諸神中，成為較次等的神。有證據顯示信徒對神聖王權的膜拜，認為君王是天神的化身；這種信仰可能是佛教轉世喇嘛的本質。苯教的神諭祭司可對應為佛教的占卜僧人。苯教教義在許多方面與藏傳佛教實際上是相同的，包括成佛與菩提心。特別值得注意的是，苯教相信大圓滿，與藏傳佛教寧瑪派(Nyingma school)相同；這些信仰認為，所有佛陀與化身之上有一個難以言喻的絕妙境界。苯教的修行制度也幾乎與藏傳佛教格魯派(Geluk school)相同。儘管如此，苯教信徒嚴格守護其無佛陀的形象。興饒(Shenrab)被視為苯教祖師，歷史上的佛陀釋迦牟尼據說是他的顯身。苯教經書有兩種：「甘珠爾(Kanjur)」大藏經，記載關於興饒的神話、教條及傳記；「康勤(Katen)」經則內含註釋、儀式及圖像作品。西藏的名稱源自於苯教。</Note_Text>
        <Note_Language>Chinese (traditional)</Note_Language>
        <Note_Contributors>
          <Note_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000250/AS-Academia Sinica</Contributor_id>
          </Note_Contributor>
        </Note_Contributors>
        <Note_Sources>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000052784/TELDAP database (2009-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
        </Note_Sources>
      </Descriptive_Note>
    </Descriptive_Notes>
    <Record_Type>Concept</Record_Type>
    <Merged_Status>Merged</Merged_Status>
    <Sort_Order>1</Sort_Order>
    <Terms>
      <Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>Bon</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000303838</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70261/Dutch</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>godsdiensten</Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70051/English</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>religion</Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>75446/Tibetan (transliterated)</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>religion</Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Noun</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000000/VP</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000205/AAT-Ned</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000088/GCI</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000045789/Goring, ed., Larousse Dictionary of Beliefs and Religions (1994)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>72</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000046363/Encyclopedia Britannica Online (1994-2001)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>accessed 2/02</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000113770/AAT-Ned (1994-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000051089/AATA database (2002-) </Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>150238 checked 26 January 2012</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000093795/Encyclopedia Britannica Online (2002-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000114707/Oxford English Dictionary Online (2002-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000083472/ULAN Nationality List (1993-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>Bon po</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000303839</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>75446/Tibetan (transliterated)</Language>
            <Preferred>Undetermined</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Used For Term</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Noun</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000000/VP</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000045789/Goring, ed., Larousse Dictionary of Beliefs and Religions (1994)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>72</Page>
            <Preferred>Alternate Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>Bön</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000303840</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>75446/Tibetan (transliterated)</Language>
            <Preferred>Undetermined</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>religion</Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Used For Term</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Noun</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000000/VP</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000045248/Bowker, Oxford Dictionary of World Religions (1997)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>158</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>bon</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000457028</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70641/Spanish</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>religión</Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000131/CDBP-SNPC</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000051373/Diccionario Espasa. Religiones y creencias (1997)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>106</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>Bonpo</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000410361</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70051/English</Language>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Used For Term</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000000/VP</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000051089/AATA database (2002-) </Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>苯教</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000565878</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>72551/Chinese (traditional)</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>宗教</Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000250/AS-Academia Sinica</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000093495/大英百科全書線上繁體中文版</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>July 17, 2012</Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>ben jiao</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000565881</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>72586/Chinese (transliterated Pinyin without tones)</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Used For Term</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000250/AS-Academia Sinica</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000052784/TELDAP database (2009-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>běn jiāo</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000565882</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>72584/Chinese (transliterated Hanyu Pinyin)</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Used For Term</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000250/AS-Academia Sinica</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000052784/TELDAP database (2009-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>pen chiao</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000565883</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>72582/Chinese (transliterated Wade-Giles)</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Used For Term</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000250/AS-Academia Sinica</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000052784/TELDAP database (2009-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>本教</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000565879</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>72551/Chinese (traditional)</Language>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Used For Term</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000250/AS-Academia Sinica</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000052784/TELDAP database (2009-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
      <Non-Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>缽教</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000565880</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>72551/Chinese (traditional)</Language>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>
            </Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Used For Term</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000250/AS-Academia Sinica</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000052784/TELDAP database (2009-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Non Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Non-Preferred_Term>
    </Terms>
    <Associative_Relationships>
      <Associative_Relationship>
        <Relationship_Type>involved with</Relationship_Type>
        <Related_Subject_ID>
          <VP_Subject_ID>300265647</VP_Subject_ID>
        </Related_Subject_ID>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
      </Associative_Relationship>
    </Associative_Relationships>
    <Subject_Contributors>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000000/VP</Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000088/GCI</Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000131/CDBP-SNPC</Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000205/AAT-Ned</Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000250/AS-Academia Sinica</Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
    </Subject_Contributors>
    <Subject_Sources>
      <Subject_Source>
        <Source>
          <Source_ID>2000051089/AATA database (2002-) </Source_ID>
        </Source>
      </Subject_Source>
      <Subject_Source>
        <Source>
          <Source_ID>2000113770/AAT-Ned (1994-)</Source_ID>
        </Source>
      </Subject_Source>
    </Subject_Sources>
  </Subject>
</Vocabulary>