<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Vocabulary xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://vocabsservices.getty.edu/Schemas/AAT/AATGetSubject.xsd">
  <Subject Subject_ID="300343684">
    <Parent_Relationships>
      <Preferred_Parent>
        <Parent_Subject_ID>300250308</Parent_Subject_ID>
        <Relationship_Type>Parent/Child</Relationship_Type>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Parent_String>Cervidae (family) [300250308], Artiodactyla (order) [300310321], Mammalia (class) [300265707], Vertebrata (subphylum) [300265720], Chordata (phylum) [300266513], Animalia (kingdom) [300249395], Eukaryota (domain) [300265677], living organisms (entities) [300390503], Living Organisms (hierarchy name) [300265673], Agents Facet [300264089]</Parent_String>
        <Hier_Rel_Type>Genus/Species-BTG</Hier_Rel_Type>
      </Preferred_Parent>
    </Parent_Relationships>
    <Descriptive_Notes>
      <Descriptive_Note>
        <Note_Text>In some classifications, Hydropotes is considered a third subfamily of the family Cervidae, along with Old World deer (subfamily Cervinae) and New World deer (subfamily Capreolinae). This subfamily was created to contain the Chinese water deer (Hydropotes inermis), a very small Asian deer of the family Cervidae (order Artiodactyla), native to fertile river bottoms in Korea and the Yangtze River (Chang Jiang) valley in China. It is the only species of deer in which males lack antlers; instead, they are armed with long, curved, and sharp upper canine teeth that protrude from the mouth. These tusks may exceed 5 cm (2 inches) in length. The water deer is also the only deer with inguinal glands. Although water deer resemble extinct primitive deer in lacking antlers, they evolved from ancestors with antlers that were subsequently lost. Their morphology indicates that they are New World deer. Males stand about 50 cm (20 inches) tall at the shoulder and weigh up to 13 kg (29 pounds); females weigh up to 11 kg (24 pounds). They have a rather uniformly colored coat, yellowish brown above and yellowish white below. The tail is very short, and there is no rump patch. Their coarse, thick coat and fur-covered ears are adaptations to cold, snowy winters.</Note_Text>
        <Note_Language>English</Note_Language>
        <Note_Contributors>
          <Note_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000000/VP</Contributor_id>
          </Note_Contributor>
        </Note_Contributors>
        <Note_Sources>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000047703/Wilson and Reeder, Mammal Species of the World (2005)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000093795/Encyclopedia Britannica Online (2002-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
        </Note_Sources>
      </Descriptive_Note>
      <Descriptive_Note>
        <Note_Text>In sommige classificaties worden de Hydropotes beschouwd als derde onderfamilie van de familie Cervidae, samen met echte herten (subfamilie Cervinae) en schijnherten (subfamilie Capreolinae). Deze subfamilie is in het leven geroepen om de Chinese waterree (Hydropotes inermis) te kunnen onderbrengen. Het betreft hier een zeer klein Aziatisch hert uit de familie Cervidae (orde Artiodactyla) dat leeft op de vruchtbare rivierbeddingen van Korea en in het dal van de Yangtze-rivier (Chang Jiang) in China. Het is de enige hertensoort waarbij het mannetje geen gewei draagt, maar voorzien is van lange, gebogen scherpe hoektanden die uit de bek steken. Deze slagtandjes zijn soms meer dan 5 cm lang. Het waterhert is bovendien het enige hert met liesklieren. Door het ontbreken van een gewei lijkt het waterhert weliswaar op uitgestorven primitieve hertensoorten, maar het ontwikkelde zich uit voorouders die aanvankelijk een gewei droegen, dat echter later verdween. De bouw duidt erop dat het schijnherten betreft. Het mannetje heeft een schofthoogte van circa 50 cm en weegt maximaal 13 kg, terwijl het gewicht van vrouwtjes maximaal 11 kg is. De vacht is vrij uniform van kleur: geelachtig bruin boven en geelachtig wit beneden. De staart is zeer kort en de vlek op het achterdeel ontbreekt. De grove, dikke vacht en met bont bedekte oren zijn aanpassingen voor koude winters met sneeuw.</Note_Text>
        <Note_Language>Dutch</Note_Language>
        <Note_Contributors>
          <Note_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000205/AAT-Ned</Contributor_id>
          </Note_Contributor>
        </Note_Contributors>
        <Note_Sources>
          <Note_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000113770/AAT-Ned (1994-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
          </Note_Source>
        </Note_Sources>
      </Descriptive_Note>
    </Descriptive_Notes>
    <Record_Type>Concept</Record_Type>
    <Merged_Status>Merged</Merged_Status>
    <Sort_Order>6</Sort_Order>
    <Terms>
      <Preferred_Term>
        <Term_Text>Hydropotes</Term_Text>
        <Display_Name>N/A</Display_Name>
        <Historic_Flag>Current</Historic_Flag>
        <Vernacular>Undetermined</Vernacular>
        <Term_ID>1000461503</Term_ID>
        <Term_Languages>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70051/English</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>subfamily</Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Noun</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70431/Latin</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>subfamily</Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Noun</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
          <Term_Language>
            <Language>70261/Dutch</Language>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
            <Qualifier>onderfamilie</Qualifier>
            <Term_Type>Descriptor</Term_Type>
            <Part_of_Speech>Undetermined</Part_of_Speech>
            <Lang_Stat>Undetermined</Lang_Stat>
          </Term_Language>
        </Term_Languages>
        <Term_Contributors>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000000/VP</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
          <Term_Contributor>
            <Contributor_id>10000205/AAT-Ned</Contributor_id>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Contributor>
        </Term_Contributors>
        <Term_Sources>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000093795/Encyclopedia Britannica Online (2002-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000047699/National Museum of Natural History, Mammal Species (2000-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000047703/Wilson and Reeder, Mammal Species of the World (2005)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
          <Term_Source>
            <Source>
              <Source_ID>2000113770/AAT-Ned (1994-)</Source_ID>
            </Source>
            <Page>
            </Page>
            <Preferred>Preferred</Preferred>
          </Term_Source>
        </Term_Sources>
      </Preferred_Term>
    </Terms>
    <Subject_Contributors>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000000/VP</Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
      <Subject_Contributor>
        <Contributor_id>10000205/AAT-Ned</Contributor_id>
      </Subject_Contributor>
    </Subject_Contributors>
  </Subject>
</Vocabulary>